GOVIND NARAYAN CHAURASIYA

Web Developer

5.8 (1.2y on-site UK) years of experience in the, education, e-commerce, telecom and sales domain building responsive websites and web applications with focus on re usability, performance, code quality, scalable, maintainable in an agile and scrum environment utilizing a test driven development approach. Learning NodeJS to grow as Full Stack Developer.

\times

chaurasia.govind@gmail.com



07847916985



Bellandur, Bangalore, India

SKILLS

JavaScript



CSS



Node



AngularJS



GIT





Webpack



Jenkins

Bootstrap

JEST

Jasmin

Karma



CI/CD





LANGUAGES

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

English

Full Professional Proficiency

French

Basic One year course -Elementary Proficiency

DOMAIN

Telecom

Education

Ecommerce

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Consultant

Virtusa

08/2016 – Present

Client - British Telecom (EE, Plusnet)

Responsibilities/Achievements

- Support and develop new features for Customer and Agent facing live applications.
- Working on AEM based application development with Angular/React.
- Opportunity to grow with a large cross functional team with Agile model.
- Engaged with client directly to grasp domain knowledge and deliver best.
- Learned Test driven development, Setting code quality checks in CI/CD environment.
- Involved in talent recruitment to grow the organization quality and size.
- Upgrading AngularJS Application to Angular.
- Trained new talents to work on Frontend technologies.

Software Engineer

Sourcebits - Ascendum Digital

07/2015 - 08/2016

Projects/Clients - Zipform, CEB, Aiva, Collegehunch, MyScout

Responsibilities/Achievements

- Served clients to develop or uplift their applications across platforms/
- Opportunity to take ownership of the project and build it from scratch.
- Learned Agile process client interaction and leadership.
- Contributed as panel to hire talents for the organization
- Delivering training sessions about Angular

Software Engineer

Edcite

05/2014 - 07/2015

Responsibilities/Achievements

- Edcite enables teachers to create high-quality, easily customizable, interactive content to fit their class.
- Developed UI, question applications and mathematical question items and mini educational games.
- Content writing Created science and math questions.
- Learned to write object oriented clean code with trending technologies like Angular JS.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Application

Pondicherry Central University

07/2011 – 05/2014

Pondicherry, India

Bangalore, India

Bangalore, India

Bangalore India

Bachelor of Science (Statistics Hons.)
Banaras Hindu University

07/2006 - 07/2010

Varanasi, India